# LALITENDU ADHIKARI

# (Operation-in-Charge)

Address Nistha, BL.111, Nandanvan Society Main

Road, Besides Golden View Apartment,

Near Raiya Circle, Rajkot, Gujarat, 360007

**Phone** 919-438-040941

E-mail lalitenduadhikari@gmail.com

Twitter https://twitter.com/sreflector85

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/sreflector85/

Having more than 6 years of experience in composite product tooling & manufacturing related to wind power & automobile sector. Professional with excellent client & project management skills. Solid organizational communication & time management skill. Managing and directing production processes while ensuring optimum utilization of resources to increase cost savings, quality, output and efficiency of production.

A skilled communicator able to maintain cultural sensitivity, establishes rapport with members of diverse groups, and promotes team cohesiveness.

<b>83</b>	Skills	
	ISO 9001:2015	Very Good
•	Six Sigma(6σ)	<b>Very Good</b>
•	Training & Development	<b>Very Good</b>
•	Value stream mapping	<b>Very Good</b>
•	Internal quality audit	<b>*** *** * * * * * * *</b>
•	Microsoft Office	Very Good
•	Documents preparation	<b>***</b> Excellent

# **Work History**



### Jul 2019 - Unit Production Head (Feb.2020 to till date)

#### Current

EPP Composites Pvt. Ltd., Rajkot, Gujarat

At EPP Composites, working as unit production head of General Moulding & Poles div. since Feb. 2020 to till date. Following are the scope of responsibilities:

- Handling Multiple projects such as Defence Barracks(BSF), different FGD plant products, cooling tower products, GRP light poles, fire & safety frp products, Products for Indian railways etc.
- Managing a team of 50 operation associates. Giving work assignments & evaluating employee performance.
- Forecasting & prioritizing monthly production & dispatch plan as per pending orders.
- Material planning as per the production plan & coordinating with the purchase team well in advance in order to avoid material delay.
- Ensuring planned targets are met
- Effectively managing risks & accessing opportunities for continuous improvement.
- Interacting regularly with cross functional departments to ensure smooth execution of operation & to meet scheduled dispatch requirements.
- Monitoring effectively unit's performance as per defined KPIs like plant capacity utilization, planning effectiveness, RMC control, on time delivery etc.
- Monitoring & handling site works as per plan.
- Hosting review meetings with management to showcase unit's performance weekly or monthly as per requirement.
- Providing necessary inputs to marketing team regarding manufacturing feasibility & taking necessary steps to get the order approved from client.
- Maintaining excellent communication with clients, providing required status of the orders, attending meetings & providing after sales support if required.
   Some of the clients handled are," Munters India Humidity Control Pvt. Ltd., Sterling & Wilson Pvt. Ltd., Adani Power Ltd., L&T Ltd., Nayara Energy Ltd., Gujarat Gas Ltd., Reliance power Ltd. etc.

#### **Achievements of Financial Year:**

- 1. Maintained Raw material consumption within benchmark.
- 2. Reduced customer complain by 80% compared to financial year 20-21.

## Operation in Charge (Jul 2019 to Jan. 2020)

EPP Composites Pvt. Ltd., Rajkot, Gujarat

- Monitoring Shop Floor planning and project execution.
- Involvement in daily meetings with management as well as in the shop floor.
- Monthly planning of material, manpower, production and dispatch.
- Monitoring plant activities and controlling material consumption as per BOM.
- Improving shop floor conditions by implementing 5'S and KAIZEN.
- Involvement in process improvement and product development.
- Presentation of unit performance in Monthly review meetings
- Developed team communications and information for annual meetings.
- Frequent communication with clients as per requirement like scheduled delivery, addressing issues if any.

# Mar 2018 - Senior Production Engineer

Jun 2019

Indutch Composites Technology Pvt. Ltd., Vadodara, Gujarat

At Indutch Composites I had the opportunity to associate with Suzlon Energy Ltd, Pioneer Wincorn Rotor Blade Manufacturing, and manufacturing of Nacelle, Spinner and other composite parts of Inox wind Ltd. and raw material kitting of LM wind power.

#### Manufacturing of Carbon Fibre Composite heated moulds for L&T Defence.

- Understanding Customer requirements by communicating with the customer as well as with the internal team.
- Arrangement of materials by proper discussion with PPC and purchase team.
- Understanding drawings released by design team and provide proper training to the shop floor team.
- Conducting process FMEA
- •Increasing value of product by increasing the performance of the product and decreasing the manufacturing cost.

# Manufacturing of Composite moulds: Web main mould & Trailing edge web mould for Vestas India Pvt. Ltd.

- •Study of designers specification for Model, Mould
- •Study of Materials consumption provided by designer
- Study of other requirements related to Project and get it done as per requirements.
- Planning of raw materials, supporting materials as per Production planning.
- •Communication of Planning across the team and update with new revisions
- •Compiles schedules and orders, such as production, work flow, and maintenance and repair.

#### Manufacturing of Rotor & Generator parts of Senvion wind energy Solutions.

- Planning for production targets and achieving the same in a limited time frame.
- Material & manpower control.
- Monitoring Daily productions and circulating the same to MR.
- Providing training to technicians as per the requirement of process.
- Handling customer visits and communicating job progress on regular basis.
- •Implementing  $6\sigma$  to the ongoing process and maintaining  $\sigma$  level throughout.

## Jul 2017- Production Shift Engineer

#### Nov 2017 Suzlon Energy Ltd., Anantapur, Andhra Pradesh

#### Manufacturing of Rotor Blade (SB-54) Unit

- Worked as Production Shift Engineer at Suzlon Energy Ltd.
- •Responsible for arrangement of materials for smooth functioning of the process.
- •Ensuring the process flow as per standard operating procedure.
- Exposure to infusion moulding process in FRP.
- Defects analysis & controlling quality.
- Providing training to the shop floor people as per the quality norms.
- Manpower handling.

## Nov 2016 - QAQC Engineer

#### May 2017 Indutch Composites Technology Pvt. Ltd., Ludhiana, Punjab

#### Manufacturing of Nacelle and Spinner Covers.

- Worked as QA-QC engineer for manufacturing of Nacelle and Spinner covers for Inox Wind Ltd.
- •Inspection of incoming raw materials, in process quality control and final inspection of finished products.
- Preparation of related documents according to the need of customer.
- •Set clearance; maximize the usage of raw material. Raising NCs and participate Root cause analysis, taking corrective action and preventive action.
- •Establishing good communications and sharing necessary suggestions with the Customer.
- •Ensuring Shop floor conditions and to provide a better technical support to the shop floor people.
- •5'S

# Feb 2016 - QAQC Engineer

#### Oct 2016 Indutch Composites Technology Pvt. Ltd., Vadodara, Gujarat

#### Manufacturing of Rotor Blade (HT-24) Unit

- Worked as QA-QC Engineer for manufacturing of rotor blade (HT-24) unit for Pioneer wincorn Pvt. Ltd.
- Making monthly tentative production planning & auditing for achieving the same. Ensuring process flow as per standard work instructions.
- Reviewing NCR and providing repairing instruction as per standard SRP.
- Defects analysis & controlling quality.
- Laboratory test for composite materials like resin, adhesive, glass fibre, etc.

#### <u>Kitting of Raw Materials for manufacturing rotor blade of LM wind power.</u>

- •Inspection of incoming materials as per standard QAP.
- Making protocols & work instruction as per standard design for newly developed project.
- Maintaining records as per the requirement.
- Raising NCs and providing repairing instruction as per standard SRP.

• Maintaining shop floor environmental conditions as per SOP and providing training to the shop floor people.

Aug 2008 - Faculty Member

Jan 2016 Apex Institute of Technology & Management, Bhubaneswar, Odisha

#### Carried out Different Electrical Engineering subjects and Labs

- Basic Electrical Engineering
- Electrical & Electronics Measurement
- Network theory
- Electrical machines (AC & DC Machines)
- Power system Engineering

# Education

Jun 2015 - AMIE (BE in Electrical): Electrical Engineering

Institution Of Engineers - Kolkata

Jan 2004 - Diploma: Electrical Engineering

Jan 2008 UCP Engineering School - Berhampur, Odisha

# Certifications

Six Sigma (60) green belt

Completed Six Sigma (6a) green belt certification programme from INDIAN STATISTICAL INSTITUTE, New Delhi in MAR. 2017.

ISO 9001:2015

Certified Internal lead Auditor from DNV GL, Vadodara.

# Languages

English

Hindi

Odia

Superior
Superior

e best

Native

I hereby declare that all the information mentioned above is true and complete to the best of my knowledge.